The count function can also be used to count
يُمكن أيضًا استخدام دالة العدد لحساب
the number of non-null records in an individual column.
عدد السجلات غير الفارغة في عمود فردي.
To illustrate this, let's take a look at the accounts table.
ولتوضيح ذلك، دعونا نلقي نظرة على جدول الحسابات.
As you can see, there are 354 rows in the accounts table.
كما ترون، يوجد 354 صفًا في جدول الحسابات.
Now, by substituting ID for the star,
والآن، من خلال استبدال معرّف النجمة،
we can see how many non-null records there are in the ID column.
يمكننا أن نرى عدد السجلات غير الخالية الموجودة في عمود المعرّف.
Let's give the column a more sensible name while we're at it.
فدعونا نمنح العمود اسمًا أكثر منطقية عندما نكون فيه.
Since there are no null values in the ID column,
ونظرًا لعدم وجود قيم فارغة في عمود المعرّف،
it returns the same result as count star.
فإنه ينتُج عن ذلك النتيجة نفسها كنجمة عدد.
Now, let's try this with a column that we know contains some null values, primary poc.
والآن، دعونا نجرّب هذا مع العمود الذي نعرف أنه يحتوي على بعض القيم الخالية، poc الرئيسي.
This time, we get a result that is nine lower than our previous result.
وهذه المرة، نحصل على نتيجة أقل تسع مرات من النتيجة السابقة.
Let's run a quick query to verify that there are nine null values in
لنقم بإجراء استعلام سريع للتحقق من وجود تسع قيم خالية في
the primary poc column.
عمود poc الأساسي.
And here they are,
وها هي،
the nine rows with null values.
الصفوف التسعة ذات القيم الخالية.
One thing you may have noticed is that count can be
يوجد شيء واحد قد تكون لاحظته، وهو أنه يمكن استخدام العدّ
used in columns with non numerical values.
في الأعمدة ذات القيم غير الرقمية.
This is not true of all aggregation functions, but it makes sense.
وهذا ليس صحيحًا في جميع دالات التجميع، لكنه منطقي.
The count function is just looking for non-null data and text is not null.
إلى جانب ذلك، تبحث دالة العدد عن البيانات غير الخالية والنص غير الخالي وحسب.
Some of the functions we're about to learn like sum and
بعض الدالات التي نوشك على تعلمها مثل المجموع
average are impossible to apply to text because,
والمتوسط، لا يمكن تطبيقها على النص،
well, how do you take the average of a bunch of account names.
فكيف يمكن أن تأخذ متوسط مجموعة من أسماء الحسابات.